Should
Следует
Severely punish this man
строго наказать этого человека
Sentence him to death
приговорить к смерти
You're not pleading for his life anymore?
Так ты уже и не просишь пощады
Yu Gong serves as Chancellor of the Imperial Academy
Юй Гун  глава Академии
Court affairs are not within his purview
государственные дела вне его компетенции
Can be charged with
можно определить
The crime of recklessly discussing court affairs
преступление вольного обсуждения государственных дел
Sentence him to beheading
приговорить к казни
Good
Хорошо
But
Но
Our dynasty
Наш двор
Has always ruled through filial piety
всегда управлял Поднебесной сыновним почтением
Yu Gong is the only son
Юй Гун  единственный сын в семье
His young son died early
его ребёнок умер в младенчестве
His father is now over seventy
его отец уже в глубокой старости
Your son thinks
Сын полагает
He could be allowed
можно позволить ему
To return home and fulfill filial duty first
сначала вернуться домой исполнить сыновний долг
After his father passes
после смерти его отца
Then carry out the execution
снова казнить
Thus both loyalty and filial piety are preserved
так проявите и верность и сыновний долг
All the people will be moved by
весь народ будет благодарен
Your Majesty's virtue
милость Его Величества
What a perfect balance of loyalty and filial piety
Прямо и верность и сыновний долг
This man's attacks against your father
А про то как он поносил твоего отца
You don't mention at all
ты и слова не сказал